<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How It Works on </title>
    <link>https://docs.barricade.io/tags/how-it-works/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How It Works on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.barricade.io/tags/how-it-works/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How Agents Work</title>
      <link>https://docs.barricade.io/getting-started/how-it-works-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.barricade.io/getting-started/how-it-works-agent/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Agents quietly monitor, without getting in the way or impacting on your server resources. There is no need for any code or configuration changes to your app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data is gathered, encrypted and sent from the agent to the Barricade platform engine; where it’s immediately analyzed for any suspicious activity - detecting web app attacks, data breaches or intrusion attempts on your server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lightweight-agent:9d5d196026c9b7320d8721a95f202636&#34;&gt;Lightweight Agent&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agent sits quietly on your server and keeps an eye on things - the heavy data analysis processes are carried out by our platform’s engine - to ensure your performance isn’t affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our design ensures that the agent does &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get in the way&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
the agent monitors and collects data, it will not block any traffic on your application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slow down your server&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
the agent focuses on lightweight tasks; formatting and transmitting data to our engine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expose your data&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
all transmitted information is encrypted with 2048-bit SSL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-way-agent:9d5d196026c9b7320d8721a95f202636&#34;&gt;One-Way Agent&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry - Barricade can’t connect to your server and execute commands. By design, the agent communicates out but Barricade can never communicate in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation:9d5d196026c9b7320d8721a95f202636&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Agent is installed via a one touch command, which fetches the code, verifies the package signature and installs the agent on your server. For step-by-step installation instructions see the &lt;a href=&#34;#installing-an-agent&#34;&gt;Installing an Agent&lt;/a&gt; guide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OS Compatibility</title>
      <link>https://docs.barricade.io/getting-started/os-requirements-compatibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.barricade.io/getting-started/os-requirements-compatibility/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Our Agent supports &lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;CentOS&lt;/strong&gt; based cloud servers - (common configurations on providers like AWS, Google Cloud Platform, DigitalOcean and Microsoft Azure).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu 14.04 LTS (64-bit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu 14.10 (64-bit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu 12.04 (64-bit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CentOS 6.5 (64-bit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CentOS 7.0 (64-bit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;windows-support:a4289c93faaa8e5b7b34d56ee7e26c25&#34;&gt;Windows Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We currently don&amp;rsquo;t support Windows servers, but it&amp;rsquo;s on our product roadmap. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to be added to our early access list for Windows, &lt;a href=&#34;https://barricade.io/about#contact-info&#34;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt; and we&amp;rsquo;ll keep you informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;running-the-agent-on-docker:a4289c93faaa8e5b7b34d56ee7e26c25&#34;&gt;Running the Agent on Docker&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently testing a new version of our agent that runs natively on Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be shipping Docker support in early 2016 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://barricade.io/about#contact-info&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;d like to get early access!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Detection Engine</title>
      <link>https://docs.barricade.io/getting-started/detection-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.barricade.io/getting-started/detection-engine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our platform engine makes decisions in real-time. Data is received from the agent and processed through statistical (machine learning) models to make decisions. When an attack is detected, the engine triggers an alert and we notify you immediately through our app and integration channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As new data comes in, the engine learns about different types of behaviors for your infrastructure and what seems to be normal behavior based on the services running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Engine is designed to distil complex machine learning concepts such as artificial neural networks, anomaly detection, and ensemble learning into consumable and actionable information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For details on the various behaviors &amp;amp; attacks that Barricade detects - &lt;a href=&#34;../security-guide&#34;&gt;see the Security Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://docs.barricade.io/getting-started/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.barricade.io/getting-started/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;video-container&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ukTAg2ecO8g&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Barricade collects data from your server with an &lt;strong&gt;Agent&lt;/strong&gt; - a simple, lightweight package that watches all network activity on your cloud server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data is encrypted and processed through Barricades&amp;rsquo; central detection &lt;strong&gt;Engine&lt;/strong&gt;, and findings are displayed in real-time in your dashboard and notification channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../src/img/getting-started/agent-chart-sm.png&#34; alt=&#34;../src/img/getting-started/agent-chart-sm.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Barricade&amp;rsquo;s Collection Workflow - gathering, processing and alerting (&lt;a href=&#34;../src/img/getting-started/agent-chart-lg.png&#34;&gt;open in full-size&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Can Agents see?</title>
      <link>https://docs.barricade.io/getting-started/what-agent-sees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.barricade.io/getting-started/what-agent-sees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The agent gathers data about activity on your servers, and transmits it securely to our engine for real-time analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Names and versions of software packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network traffic that goes in and out of your server from the network layer all the way up to the application layer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration files for applications like Nginx and SSH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All transmitted data is &lt;strong&gt;encrypted with 2048-bit SSL&lt;/strong&gt;, and promptly analyzed by our engine to check for any security issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever DevOps tools you run, Barricade will detect and observe but not interfere - be it Chef, Puppet, Ansible, docker-composer, Beanstalk, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this information, Barricade tells you immediately if someone is trying to break in, if data is leaving your network when it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t, if your server software is affected by known exploits and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>